YYeTs人人影视字幕组出品
更多原创字幕翻译 请登陆www.YYeTs.com
■
时间轴： godwuwen
后期： 鱼骨头  字幕总监： YY
■
翻译： vero  一块二  阿蘅阿蘅  独醉
后期： 鱼骨头  字幕总监： YY
■
校对： YY    后期： 鱼骨头  字幕总监： YY
老爸老妈浪漫史
第七季  第五集
孩子们  在2011年10月
Kids, in October 2011,
你们的罗宾阿姨接受了心理治疗
your Aunt Robin was in therapy.
进展一反常态地顺利
And against all logic, it was actually going well.
可这是为什么
But why?
为什么我总找理由让自己不幸福
Why-why am I constantly looking for reasons not to be happy?
也许是因为幸福圆满的大结局
Maybe because the idea of finally being happy...
反而让你畏惧
terrifies you.
哥们  你这话真是经典
Bro, you are killing it today.
确实很有疗效
We got something good here.
我绝对可以克服害怕被抛弃的心理了
We are totes gonna conquer my fear of abandonment!
我不能再见你了
I can't see you anymore.
说得好
Nice.
"不会吧  你要抛弃我了"
"Oh, no! You're abandoning me!"
不会吧  你真要抛弃我了
Oh, no. You're abandoning me
对不起  我要搬到阿拉斯加去了
I'm sorry. I'm moving to Alaska.
故事原本到这儿就结束了
And that might have been the end of it.
但一周后...
But a week later...
凯文
Kevin?!
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
其实  搬到阿拉斯加是骗你的
Okay, look, I lied to you about moving to Alaska.
我必须得回避你
I-I had to stop seeing you.
为什么
Why?
因为我觉得你很有爱
'Cause I think you're cute.
职业规定  如果我对你有感觉
And ethically, I can't be your therapist
就不能当你的心理医生了
if I'm attracted to you.
我懂了  你抛弃我这个病人
Oh, I get it. You dump me as a patient
是为了好跟我约会
just so you can ask me out?
我不会跟你约会的
I'm not gonna ask you out.
你不会吗
You're not?
不行  我们是在治疗期间认识的
No. We met in therapy.
跟病人约会对我而言不合适
It's inappropriate for me to date a patient.
总之  很高兴见到你
Anyway, it was nice seeing you.
等等
Hey, wait.
怎样才算"约会"
How do you define "Date"?
两个人一起吃饭
Two people having a meal together,
坐在一张餐桌的两端
sitting across the table
对彼此眉来眼去
making googly eyes at each other...
那如果是两个人单独吃饭  肩并肩坐着
What about two people eating alone, sitting side by side,
对着咖啡机眉来眼去呢
making googly eyes at the coffee maker?
可以  那就不是约会
Okay, it's not a date.
没错  不是约会
Exactly. Not a date.
于是罗宾和凯文  在那周的每天早上
And so Robin and Kevin had breakfast alone,
都肩并肩坐着  各自吃早餐
side by side every day that week.
直到后来...
Until finally...
抱歉  拦不到出租车
Sorry. No cabs.
我狂奔了40个街区过来的
Ran 40 blocks all the way here.
可能路上还撞到了一位老太太
May have knocked an old lady into the street,
我也不清楚  我没空回头看
don't know, I didn't look back.
我们来场真正的约会吧
Let's just go on a real date.
好  这个主意不错
Yeah, that might be a good idea.
湿材终于点燃爱火
Finally!
我迫不及待要去看那部电影了
Oh, I can't wait to see that movie.
-好看吗  -酷毙了
- Is it good? - Awesome.
等等  打个比方
Wait, totally hypothetically,
你会喜欢那种颠覆性结局
do you like movies with a shocking twist
最后主角全都死光光的电影吗
where all the main characters die at the end?
-喜欢  -那你会爱死这部电影的
- Yes. - You will love this movie.
-嗨  大伙  -嗨  马修  怎么了
- Hey, guys.- Hey, Marshall.What's up?
我告诉你们怎么了
Well, I'll tell you what's up.
你们都知道  我的老板加里森・库兹
You know how my boss, Garrison Cootes,
那个全世界最著名的环境律师吧
is,like, the most famous environmental lawyer in the world?
是...吧
Yeah...
我是说  除了他可能还有别人
I mean, it's him or the other guy.
-安东尼・霍威尔先生吗  --是...吧
- Sir Anthony Howel? - Yeah...
反正他也是个大人物  好吗
Anyway, he's an important guy, okay?
所以今天上班的时候
And so today at work,
我试图在他面前表现强硬
I was trying to show him that I'm tough.
我最近都在琢磨格鲁伯药业公司
I've been thinking about this settlement offer
开给我们的和解报价会有多少
we're about to get from Gruber Pharmaceuticals.
如果少于两千万
If it's anything less than $20 million,
我会揪住这些公司的地球强奸犯...
then I'm gonna grab those corporate Earth rapists by their...
好了  我要打断一下
Okay, I'm just gonna say something.
我现在肚子里怀着孩子
I'm growing a child in my belly,
孩子刚刚长出耳朵
a child that just developed ears.
这是件很薄的毛衣
This is a very thin sweater.
所以如果你非要说这事
So please, if you must tell your story...
麻烦注意用词
just make it cheerful.
注意用词
Cheerful.
马修原文猜测如下
好吧  那我会揪住这些公司的...
Okay...Then I'm gonna grab those corporate...
我要揪住那些地球强奸犯
I'm gonna grab those corporate Earth rapists
员工们
employees...
抓住他们出汗摇摆的...
by their sweaty, dangling...
双手
hands...
把潮了吧唧吊在裤裆里的蛋蛋
by their sweaty, dangling Balls.
用力挤压  直到这些贪婪的...
and squeeze until those greedy sons of...
父母养的
parents...
用力蹂躏  直到那帮贪婪的孙子
and squeeze until those greedy sons of bitches
意识到我是这世上最勇猛的...
realize that I'm the baddest mother...
热爱自然的小愤青
nature lover around.
意识到我才是地球上最坏的混蛋
realize that I'm the baddest mother fucker.
这就像是在看TBS台的《早餐俱乐部》
It's like watching The Breakfast Club on TBS.
美国电视频道TBS  会把脏话消音掉或剪辑掉
那他怎么说
So what did he say?
马修  弯下腰来  我好搂着你的肩说话
Marshall, bend down so I can put my arm around you.
这个高度差不多了  很好
That's all the way down. That's good.
格鲁伯药业公司的员工
Gruber Pharmaceuticals is a company full
都是一群尽职尽责的善良的人们
of well-meaning people doing their jobs,
就像你我一样
just like you and me.
各位  恐怕加里森・库兹变软弱了
Guys, I'm afraid that Garrison Cootes has gone soft!
他就像是只泰迪熊
He's like a teddy bear!
是像泰迪熊  还是伊渥克熊
A teddy bear or an Ewok?
Ewoks是《星际大战6 绝地归来》里帮助叛军击退帝国守军的毛怪
平日在村子里可爱惹人怜
You know, cute and cuddly around the village,
但一旦战争打响
but once the battle starts...
他会挥舞着巨大的木槌
He'll smash in your metal skull
击碎你的金盔铁甲
with giant swinging logs.
马修
Marshall!
好吧  他会一直抱着你
Okay, he'll hug you
直到你同意和平关闭死星
until you agree to peaceably shut down the Death Star.
嗨  宝贝
Hi, sweetie.
你们在说些什么呢
What are we all talking about?
伊渥克熊
Ewoks.
我讨厌那种熊
Ugh, I hate the Ewoks.
知道伊渥克熊在那部电影里  唯一的看点是什么吗
The only good thing about Ewoks in that movie?
就是其中几只死翘翘了
You got to see some of them die.
我想来杯扎啤
Well, I fancy a pint.
诺拉讨厌伊渥克熊
Nora hates Ewoks.
我必须跟她分手
Well, I have to break up with her.
各位  你们告诉她的时候婉转点
Be gentle when you tell her, guys.
我到了维加斯再联系你们
I'll call you from Vegas.
告诉我情况如何  闪了
Tell me how it went. Okay.
够了  巴尼
Okay, Barney!
乖乖坐下
Sit down!
不喜欢伊渥克族
Not liking Ewoks
不是什么分手的理由
is no reason not to date somebody.
没错  我是说
Yeah, I mean,
谁会乖乖遵守准则呀  对吧
who knows what the rules are, ya know?
你跟一个不喜欢伊渥克族的女孩约会
I mean, you're dating a girl who doesn't like Ewoks,
我跟我的前任心理医生约会
I'm dating my former therapist.
这太有失身份了
We are gentlemen of Harvard!
-这没什么大不了的  -罗宾
- It's not a big deal! - Robin,
如果你去问一百个人
if you asked a hundred people,
"最不该约会的对象是谁"
"Who's the worst person you could possibly date?"
他们都会说  "你的心理医师"
They'd all say, "Your therapist."
当然也会有人说是"巴尼"
Except the ones saying "Barney."
说得也有道理
Yeah, that tracks
我得走了
Well, I should get going.
明天我要带学生去实地勘察
I got the big field trip tomorrow.
实地勘察吗
Field trip?
是的  我要到巨人银行大楼的建筑工地
Yeah. I'm taking my Intro to Architecture class
实地上我的建筑入门课
to the GNB Tower construction site.
我试图让他们对
I'm trying to get them interested
建筑师这个职业产生兴趣
in architecture as a career.
为什么  难道我们这没别的大楼了吗
Why? Are we running out of buildings?
还是没有比他们更无聊的人了
Are we running out of boring people?
各位  这可是件大事  好不好
Guys, this is a big deal, okay?
哪怕我只让一个学生
If I can get just one kid interested in
燃起当建筑师的兴趣
becoming an architect...
好吧  我要打断你下
Okay, I'm just gonna stop you right there.
泰德  这只是个入门课
Ted, it's an Intro class.
是啊  别指望在一个入门课上演《为人师表》的戏码
Yeah, don't try to Stand and Deliver an Intro class.
Stand and Deliver 根据真人真事改编 表彰优良教师的动人电影
没人会因为要寻求人生方向去上入门课
Nobody takes an Intro class to get on any other path
除了寻求解决宿醉的良方
but the path to not being hungover anymore.
我就在某某学入门课上学到这个
I learned that in my Intro to something-ology class.
对于某某学来说无所谓
Well that's fine for something-ology,
但明早九点整
but tomorrow at 9:00 a.M. Sharp
建筑学入门课就要实地勘察了
Intro to Architecture is going on a field trip!
全班两百人都会到齐哦
All 200 of 'em.
现在是9点45分
Well, it's 9:45.
我猜  另外170人应该是迷路了吧
I guess the other 170 of you got lost,
那我们就开始吧
so we'll just start.
有人可能会说  你们选这门课
Now, some might say you guys are just taking this class
是因为简单
because it's easy
又或是你们把建筑学误以为是考古学
or because you've confused architecture with archaeology
以为我们今天会像《夺宝奇兵》一样去探险
and think we're gonna do some cool Indiana Jones stuff today.
但我觉得
But I think that...
我觉得或许
I think just maybe,
我们当中会有人成为未来的建筑师
we got some future architects in the house.
你们谁以后想当建筑师呢
Show of hands: who's thinking about a career
举个手
in architecture?
好吧  今天  形势将会逆转
Well, today, all that's gonna change.
跟我来
Follow me.
对不起
Hey. Uh, sorry,
没有通行证不能入场
nobody gets in here without a site pass.
没事  我是泰德・莫斯比
It's okay, I'm Ted Mosby,
这栋楼的建筑师
the architect of this building.
我不管你是不是这栋楼的考古学家
I don't care if you're the archaeologist of this building.
此处禁止参观
Site's closed.
撤
Moving on!
那天早上  格鲁伯药业公司
That morning, Marshall's firm
将开出一个和解报价给马修的事务所
was getting the settlement offer from Gruber Pharmaceicals,
马修迫切想看到泰迪熊变身成伊渥克熊
and Marshall couldn't wait to see the teddy bear turn into an Ewok.
格鲁伯药业公司把有毒物质倒进青蛙溪
Gruber Pharmaceuticals dumped toxic waste into Frog Creek,
这是鳟鱼河的一条支流  会流入清水湖
a tributary of the Trout River that feeds into Clearwater Lake.
现在这个三个地方  因为污染都要改名了
All three which now need new names.
是时候为地球母亲打一场胜战
So it's time to win one for Mother Earth.
让我们把那些垃圾干掉  好吗
Let's take out the trash, shall we?!
-好  -好的  每个人拿一个袋子
- Yes! - All right, everyone grab a bag.
蓝色是可循环  绿色是混合垃圾
Blue is recycling, green, compost.
出发
There we go.
希拉
Sheila...
说说你们的报价吧
we're ready to hear your offer.
24,000美元
$24,000?
还不错  挺合理的
Yeah , that seems reasonable.
孩子们  在我带着25个建筑入门班的学生
Kids, I was wandering the city
在这座城市里闲逛时
with 25 Intro to Architecture students
巴尼叔叔救了我一把
when your Uncle Barney came to my rescue.
各位  目睹一栋楼的建成  并没那么激动人心
Okay, guys, seeing a building get built, not that exciting.
真正令人激动的是财务状况
What's really exciting is the financial side of...
坐下  泰德  交给我吧
Sit down, Ted, I got this.
嘿  怪胡子  关灯
Hey, Weird Beard, lights!
大学  是个令人迷茫的时期
College... it's a confusing time.
完了
Oh, no.
研究表明  83%的大学生
Studies show that 83% of all college students
迫切地需要
desperately need...
性教育课程
sex lessons!
开灯
Lights!
巴尼  他们是青涩纯情的18岁
Barney, these are 18-year-olds!
泰德  他们是蠢蠢欲动的18岁
Ted, these are 18-year-olds!
你已经有女朋友了
You have a girlfriend.
但她不喜欢伊渥克熊
But she doesn't like Ewoks!
-那又怎样  -那又怎样
- So what? - So what?!
贾斯汀・比伯[发型像]  关灯
Bieber, lights!
1983年  乔治・卢卡斯把伊渥克熊带给了全世界
In 1983, George Lucas introduced the world to the Ewoks,
是恩多第二颗卫星上的一个生物种族
a race of creatures indigenous to the second moon of Endor.
电影里没有详细介绍
Now, the Ewoks have a rich back-story
伊渥克熊的背景
that the movie didn't really go into.
巴尼  要不你直接跳到
Barney, why don't you just skip
你和诺拉的那一段吧
to the part about you and Nora?
好吧
Fine.
对了
Ah, yes.
最终  伊渥克熊把星球大战的影迷分为两类
Ultimately, Ewoks split Star Wars fandom into two camps:
在此之前出生的  以及1973年5月25号之后出生的
those born before, and those born after May 25, 1973:
伊渥克熊分界线
the Ewok Line.
在伊渥克熊分界线左侧出生的人
Anyone born on this side of the Ewok Line was
至少绝地武士大10岁
at least ten years old when Jedi came out,
所以已经老到不喜欢那种甜腻可爱的东西
and thus too old for something so cloying and cute.
而出生在这半边的人
Anyone born on this side
都喜欢伊渥克熊  为什么呢
loved the Ewoks because, why?
因为它们会让你想起
They reminded you of...
泰迪熊吗
Our teddies?
它们会让你想起泰迪熊
They remded you of your teddies.
谢谢你  吉娜
Thank you, Gina.
你怎么知道她的名字
How do you know her name?
所以  根据伊渥克熊分界线的不二定律
And so... by the immutable laws of the Ewok Line,
我29岁的女朋友讨厌伊渥克熊
my 29-year-old girlfriend who hates Ewoks
那她肯定至少得有  37岁了
must in fact be no younger than... 37.
只比威尔的妈妈小一岁
That's only a year younger than Will's mom.
你怎么知道我妈的名字  下课
How do you know my mom? Class dismissed!
我要一个人静一静
I need to be alone.
好吧  我们撤
All right, we're moving on.
我能跟着吗
Ooh, can I come?
宝贝
Hey, baby.
提醒你一声  我们4点约了桑娅医生
Hey, I just want to remind you we have Dr. Sonya at 4:00.
我会去的  抱歉
I'll be there. I'm sorry.
我现在很郁闷
I'm just... I'm bummed.
我们今天拿到和解金了
We got our settlement offer today:
一个10亿美元的大公司只给我们2万4千美元
$24,000 from a billion-dollar company.
哇  那你公司的人肯定很不开心
Wow. I take it people aren't happy about that.
我们赢了  大家来喝香槟吃蛋糕吧
We won! Champagne and cake for everybody!
他们在庆祝
They're celebrating.
我是说  这太离谱了
I mean, it's crazy.
我们根本不配吃蛋糕
We have no right to be eating cake.
你那儿有蛋糕  我马上到
There's cake?! I'm on my way!
与此同时  史上最烂的实地勘察仍在进行
Meanwhile, the worst field trip of all time was still trucking.
好了  这同样激动人心  是吧
All right, this, this is exciting, okay?
我就在这个房间
This is the very room
设计出巨人国家银行的大楼
where I had the idea for the GNB Tower.
韦伯字典对“灵感”的定义是
Now, Webster's defines "Inspiration" As...
等下  页面还在缓冲
Hold on. It's still loading.
嘿  室友
Uh, hey, roomie.
罗宾  你在这儿干嘛
Robin! Hey, what are you doing here?
我正入"佳境"呢
Well, I was about to get my swerve on.
是吗
You were?
你就是那个心理医生
So you're the therapist.
假扮心理医生
You know, it's one thing to pretend to be a shrink
伺机和病人上床  这样很正常
and bang your patients. That's normal.
但如果真是医生与病人的关系
But to do it for real?
就有点别扭了  兄弟
A little creepy, bro.
够了  这有什么好别扭的
Okay, it's not creepy.
是...够别扭的
Ehhhh... it's creepy.
同学们  举手表决
Class, show of hands:
有谁觉得和自己的心理医生约会很别扭
Who thinks it's creepy to date your therapist?
-压倒性胜利  -滚出去
- Pollstered. - Get out!
好吧  我们撤
All right. We're moving on!
同学们  在左侧
So, class, to your left,
你们会看到一些设计精美的
you will see some excellent examples of
窗户样本
what we'd call windows.
我们现在要去哪里
So where are we going now?
我不知道
I have no idea.
这就是场灾难
This is a disaster.
有些人已经想回家了
Some of them are already starting to go home.
即使无意间多了个来旅游的德国家庭
Although we seem to have picked up a German family.
等等  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
罗宾和她的心理医生约会的事
That thing with Robin and her creepy therapist
让我灵光一现
gave me an idea.
泰德  我们可以一次性解决
Ted, we have here a way to solve
我们以前所有的争论
every single debate we've ever had!
看看这些样本
I mean, just look at the sample:
男人  女人  黑人  亚洲人  德国人
guys, girls, blacks, Asians, a German family.
哪里去找这么有代表性的集体
You can't pay for that kind of focus group!
通心粉沙拉真的是一种沙拉吗
Is macaroni salad really a salad?
不同意的请举手
Hands up if you say "No."
雅各布还是爱德华
Jacob or Edward?
谁同意爱德华
Who says Edward?
看到没  我都说了
Ha, ha. See? I told you.
是爱德华・詹姆斯・欧莫斯
It's Edward James Olmos.
Edward James Olmos  美国著名导演兼演员
你是愿意和死人做爱
Would you rather have sex with a dead human being
-还是和活人  -老兄
- or a live an...? - Dude.
-怎么了 -你有没有底线啊
- What? - Find the line.
大卫・哈塞尔霍夫是不是很优秀
Who thinks David Hasselhoff is awesome?
美国著名的电影电视演员及歌手  代表作《霹雳游侠》
看来是真的
Hmm. It's true.
我想到一个  如果你在和一个女孩子约会
Okay. I've got one. If you're dating a girl,
她谎报了年龄
and she lies about her age,
你们会和她分手吗
who says break up with her?
对对  但是如果她撒谎的对象
Yes, yes, but what if the person she's lying to
是一个出了名地在乎年龄的人呢
is notoriously shallow about age?
但是如果在刚开始谈恋爱的时候
Okay, but what if early in our relationship,
她就郑重说过
she made a really big deal
不能对对方撒谎
about wanting to not lie to each other?
如果她很性感呢
What if she's hot?
谁想要五块钱
Who wants five bucks?
压倒性胜利
Pollstered!
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
算了吧  太别扭了
Okay, this is creepy.
跟克里斯平・格洛弗一样别扭
It's Crispin Glover creepy.
Crispin Glover  美国演员  在电影中常常扮演性格怪僻的人
你是我的病人
You were my patient.
你向我敞开心扉
You shared intimate stuff.
这好像和你的妇科医生约会一样
It would be like dating your gynecologist.
你当时很脆弱
You were vulnerable.
我们不能当作没事发生
That's not something we can move past.
那倒是
Guess not.
和自己的妇科医生约会  也不好吗
So, dating your gyno, that's bad, too?
罗宾
Oh, Robin.
开个玩笑嘛
Kidding!
看  又一个蛋糕
Look, we've got another one!
来  吃一口嘛
Come on, have a bite.
不吃  这是原则问题
No, it's a matter of principle.
不管这蛋糕有多好吃
I don't care how good it is,
我绝对不会再吃第三块了
I'm not gonna have a third piece of cake!
朋友们  你们今天玩得都很尽兴
Okay, guys, you all had a lot of fun today,
现在  为了让大家更尽兴
but now it's time... to have even more fun!
再来一个蛋糕
Another cake!
又来一个
Another cake?!
你们都怎么了
What is the matter with you people?!
今天我们接受的和解金就是一堆灼热的[狗屎]
That settlement today was a flaming pile of...[shit]
小狗狗
puppies...
没有着火  只是发烧
that aren't on fire!
睁大眼看看  环境都成什么样了
Look at what's happening to the environment,
我们却在这里玩游戏
and we're here doing the limbo?
limbo stick把杠子越放越低  要弯下身子探过去的游戏
我们真该为自己感到耻辱
I mean, we should be ashamed of ourselves!
先生  我的意思是...
Sir, all I meant was...
十年之后
Ten years from right now,
外面房间里的人都会死去
everyone outside in that bullpen will be dead.
什么
What?
马修  我看了最近的研究
I've seen the latest research, Marsh.
我一直都在强调
You know how I'm always saying
拯救地球为时未晚
it's not too late to save the planet?
其实已经晚了
It's too late to save the planet.
我们无能为力
There's nothing to do but sit back
只能等待末日到来
and await our inevitable doom.
天啊   彩饰陶罐
Oh, my goodness, a Pinata
墨西哥人过圣诞节或生日将玩具糖果等礼物盛在此种罐内
再悬于天花板上  由蒙住眼的儿童用棒击破
拉里  再给我一分钟  谢谢
Just give me one minute, Larry. Thank you.
荒谬却又躲不掉的末日
Our grotesque, inevitable doom!
当然你现在不能告诉大家
Now, of course, you can't go around telling all the people
环境保护主义已是日薄西山
that the good ship Environmentalism has sailed off into the sunset.
那会引起恐慌
There would cause a panic.
相反  我们要做的
So, instead, what we do is,
上班的时候  保持微笑
we come to work, we put on a happy face,
趁太阳的辐射还没把我们烤干
and we sue the big guys
趁海水没有把我们淹没
for just enough money for some cake
我们就告告大公司的状
before the unfiltered rays of the sun fry us like chalupas,
捞点钱吃点蛋糕吧
and our lungs fill up with salt water,
反正最后都是一死
and we all die!
蛋糕很好吃  世界很美好
Mmm. This cake is delicious. Everything's fine.
今天太糟糕了
Ugh, this day sucks.
凯文和我拜拜了
Kevin and I are kaputski.
这也叫糟吗
You think that's bad?
世界末日就快来临了
The world is coming to an end.
那也叫糟吗
You think that's bad?
我的女朋友37岁了
My girlfriend is 37!
我的实地勘测之旅不如我预期中好
And my field trip is not going as well as I'd hoped.
今天太糟糕了
This day sucks.
莫斯比教授  实地勘察结束了吗
Professor Mosby, is the field trip over?
我们想回家了
We'like to go home.
已经结束了
Yeah, it's over.
再见[德语]
Auf wiedersehen.
我只不过想启发他们
I just wanted to inspire them,
就像我的教授曾经启发我一样
you know, like my professors inspired me.
可你看现在  一天就这么结束了
But here we are, at the end of the day...
同学们  问一句
Hey, class, quick question.
这里有谁想成为建筑师
Uh, is anyone here thinking of becoming an architect?
真的吗
Really?
是的  兄弟
Yeah, dude.
我的意思是  所有工作都很烂
I mean,all jobs suck,
可现在是下午四点
but it's 4:00 in the afternoon,
你却跟朋友在酒吧胡混
and you're out at a bar with your friends,
所以你这行也不见得太差
so the hours can't be that bad.
所以
So...
不好说  我会考虑下的
yeah, I don't know, I'd think about it.
终于说动一个了
I got through to you.
前提是  当DJ没戏的话
I mean, that is, if becoming a deejay doesn't pan out.
你会成为一名伟大的建筑师
You are gonna be a great architect.
他后来成为了一名DJ
He became a deejay.
罗宾  你来这儿干嘛
Robin, what are you doing here?
-我说了不能再做你的心理医生  -我知道
- I told you I can't be your therapist. - I know.
今天  我是你的心理医生
Today, I am your therapist.
什么
What?
你也说了
You said yourself,
我总找理由让自己不幸福
I'm always looking for reasons not to be happy.
我在努力改变这点
Well, I'm trying to change that.
如果我们不能在一起的原因
So, if the only reason we can't be together
是因为在初相识的两个钟头里
is because I was in a vulnerable place
我向你诉说了心底的秘密
for the first two hours we knew each other
那么应该换你  向我敞开心扉两小时
then that is two hours of vulnerability you owe me.
坐下吧
Sit down.
好吧
Okay.
不过先提醒你  我可是专业医生
Okay, but I must warn you, as a professional,
-不吃那一套  -先跟我说说你妈吧
- I'm immune to...- Tell me about your mother.
她就是个控制狂
Everything she says is a manipulation!
我7岁的时候
When I was seven years old...
库兹先生
Mr. Cootes.
我一直在想你昨天说的话
Listen, I've been thinking a lot about what you said yesterday,
你说最后大家都是死路一条
about how we're all gonna die.
我不会死的
Oh, I'm not gonna die.
我在科罗拉多买了个废弃矿井
I bought an old mine shaft in Colorado.
过去半年  我储备了充足的储备粮
I've spent the last six months filling it with canned goods,
步枪  还有全五季《周五夜现场》
assault rifles and all five seasons of Friday Night Lights.
首先我要说  第二季太烂了不用看
Okay, first of all, you can skip season two.
其次  我们谈话后
Second of all, after our talk...
我差点儿就决定放弃原则
I came pretty close to giving up myself.
但随后我陪老婆去看医生
But then I went to the doctor with my wife...
然后
and...
我看到了这个
I saw this.
男孩还是女孩
Boy or girl?
不知道
I don't know.
不过我十分确定的是  我要坚持原则
But I know I sure as hell can't give up now.
如果你只是想找个
So, if you're just looking for someone
没原则的人陪你玩游戏的话
to hold the other end of the limbo stick,
limbo stick腰力好的才能过 不适合高个子玩
那你就找错人了  知道为什么吗
you got the wrong guy for the job, and you know why?
因为你比同事都高上一米吗
'Cause you're three feet taller than everyone in this office?
不是  因为如果我打算在这儿工作
No. Because if I am gonna work here,
那么明早第一件事
then first thing tomorrow morning,
就是去找格鲁伯药业公司
I'm walking down to Gruber Pharmaceuticals,
并拒绝他们的赔偿提议
and I'm rejecting their offer.
即便是孤军奋战  我也义无反顾
Even if I have to do it myself.
听我说  我想告诉你  我知道了
Listen, I want you to know... I know.
知道什么
Know what?
诺拉
Nora.
巴尼
Barney.
诺拉
Nora.
有话就直说
Just say what you're gonna say!
我知道你很老了
I know you're old!
我纠结了这个问题很久
And I've been struggling with it,
可当我一看见你
but when I look at you...
我突然就无所谓了  因为我是真心喜欢你
I don't care, because I really like you.
而且以37岁高龄来说  你可真是前凸后翘
And because for 37, you are keeping it toit!
你以为我37岁了
You think I'm 37?
如果你真是29岁
Well, if you were really 29,
那你第一次看见伊渥克熊时
then you would have been a little kid
必然是还是个孩子  是孩子就必然会喜欢它们
the first time you saw the Ewoks and you would have loved them.
巴尼  我去年才开始看《星球大战》系列
Barney, I didn't see any of the Star Wars movies until last year.
你呀你  29岁万岁
You... you're 29!
还有一年美好时光
You still have one good year left.
-什么  -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
拉文是神经外科医生
But Naveen's the neurosurgeon,
所以理所当然  他是个宝贝疙瘩
so of course he gets all the attention!
拉文好聪明哦
Oh, Naveen is so smart,
他帮人的大脑做手术
he operates on people's brains!
您猜怎么着  妈
Well, guess what, Mom?!
我治的可是人的思想
I treat the human mind!
时间到了
Our time is up.
这样不行
I don't think this is gonna work.
我把你吓傻了吧
I scared you off, didn't I?
不  我是说我不能继续治疗你了
No, I mean, I don't think I can be your therapist.
你太有爱了
You're really cute.
第二天
The next day,
马修孤身深入格鲁伯药业的虎穴
Marshall returned to Gruber Pharmaceuticals alone.
你们已经承认污染了湖水
I mean, you admit that you polluted the lake.
我们有证据
We got the evidence.
我们有图表
We got the charts.
有鱼
The fish...
鱼
Fish, huh?
鱼很诡异
Fish are weird.
你们有琢磨过鱼的名字吗
You ever think about the names of fish?
拜托
I mean, come on.
鲤鱼[有找茬儿的意思]
Carp.
加里森  想不到你大驾光临啊
Garrison, what a nice surprise.
你的高徒正在
Your star apprentice was just, uh.
不知所云
"Floundering."
说了点鱼的小笑话
Little, little fish humor
娱乐大众
for you guys.
进展不太顺利
It was not going well.
我是来拒绝你们的二万四的
I'm here to turn down the 24,000.
加你五百也是可以商量的
Well, I can maybe get you 24,500.
不  够  多
Not... good... enough.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
战场  孩子
To war, son.
我们要奔赴战场
We're going to war.
我们要去拯救地球吗
We're going to save the planet.
孩子们  我们知道  他们做到了
And kids, as we now know, they did.
几周前
你知道昨晚放什么了吗
Hey, you know what was on last night?
《为人师表》  太好看了
Stand and Deliver. So good.
雅各布・詹姆斯・奥莫斯  怎么没见他了
Whatever happened to Jacob James Olmos?
谁
Who?
雅各布・詹姆斯・奥莫斯  怎么没见他了
Jacob James Olmos. Whatever happened to that guy?
没有这个人
He never existed.
人家叫爱德华・詹姆斯・奥莫斯[泰德是对的]
It's Edward James Olmos.
你差个名就对了
You're Olmos correct.
他就叫雅各布・詹姆斯・奥莫斯
It's Jacob James Olmos.
-爱德华・詹姆斯・奥莫斯  -雅各布・詹姆斯・奥莫斯
- It's Edward James Olmos. - Jacob James Olmos.
-爱德华・詹姆斯・奥莫斯  -开什么玩笑
- Edward James Olmos. - You're joking, right...?
-你是说真的吗  严肃点  -雅各布・詹姆斯・奥莫斯
- Are you serious...?seriously. - Jacob James Olmos.